Creating a Defect Opportunity Matrix
Welcome back to this session on defect opportunities.
We we’re talking about the Golden Spur.
Now, another way to be able to organize those defect opportunities, could be categorically.
For example, I got a tab called feed, tack, animals, tools,
vehicles, buildings, notes, and so on.
Let's go to tack. Tack is the leather stuff like saddles and so on, that we use
with the horses. For example, we have things in tack called lead ropes.
I’ll zero in on this, so we get a bigger picture here.
Lead ropes, halters, saddles, bridels, bits, tie downs, roping reins, split reins, pads,
sheets for the horses, heavy sheets, ropes, clippers.
These are the ropes, we rope the cows with. Clippers to trim their hair.
Shoeing tools, hoof picks, vet supplies. The list goes on and on.
Now with those, I've gotta do accounting, organization, cleanliness, conditioning,
missing parts, loose parts, organization. See, stitching, silver, broken, or not.
Those are my defect categories. So, these right here constitute the focus.
This is the defect category. And the opportunity is the intersect.
Organization of the halters, for example.
How about cleanliness of the saddles? That's a defect opportunity.
How about for my bridels? Are they missing parts?
So that constitutes a defect opportunity, if there's a missing part on a bridel.
Like a screw holding the leather to the bit, let's say.
Now another one, might be the silver on the saddles.
Is it dull, not very shiny. That's a defect opportunity.
Now, take tools for example. Over here under tools.
Again blowing this up, so we can see.
We have lifts, welders. In this case, a blue welder.
We have to account for it. Is it clean? Is the motor operating?
Does this thing have batteries? No. Does it have blades? Does it require lubrication? Yes.
So, that is true. It does have motors. That's true.
Should it be clean? Yes. Are there keys with it? No.
Does it require adjustment? Yes.
So, you see there, I'm identifying the potential defect categories
associated with each element.
Portable drills, cut off saws, so on.
These are all the tools needed around the ranch, just like the tack.
So, if I’m going to improve the quality around the Golden Spur,
I gotta benchmark where my performance is at, and where I want to go.
Can't do that without knowing my defect opportunities.
It’s kinda like saying, can't tell the players without a the program.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.